Optimus, you are not going to believe this.
擎天柱 说了你也不信
I just pinpointed the location of the Decepticon warship.
我刚刚完成了对霸天虎战舰的精确定位
How did you penetrate their cloaking technology?
他们的隐身技术被你破解了吗？
I didn't.
我没破解
I was experimenting the variable frequency wavelengths when I stumbled upon it.
我是在试验各种频段波长时 偶然发现的
Even still, their ship must be experiencing some kind of electromagnetic breach.
而且 他们的飞船一定受到了某种电磁破坏
With Megatron deceased and the element of surprise...
威震天死了 趁他们疏于防范…
We can cause some serious damage.
我们可以来个当头一棒
Also in the same frequency, an Autobot emergency beacon.
同一个频率上 还发现了汽车人紧急信标
The Decepticons can wait, there maybe Autobots in distress.
霸天虎的事先放一放 很可能有汽车人遇难
Rachet, bring your medical kit.
救护车 带上医疗包
A crash landing, buried here for centuries.
飞船迫降 看来已经坠毁几百年了
If they traveled in stasis mode, there may be survivors.
如果他们是在休眠模式下航行 或许还有幸存者
Optimus, these Autobots didn't perish in the crash.
擎天柱 这些汽车人并不是死于飞船失事
They are displaying the effects of a virus.
他们的症状…像是感染了病毒
This is a plague ship.
这是艘瘟船
Don't touch anything.
什么都别碰！
The virus could still be active.
病毒可能还有活性
No!
不！
Cybonic plague.
是灰死病
It's only contagious if contact is made with the infected energeon.
只有在接触被感染能量时才会被传染
What was a plague doing in an Autobot spaceship?
汽车人飞船里怎么会有瘟疫呢？
Its passengers were infected.
飞船上有被感染的乘客
The virus wiped out millions on Cybertron during the great war.
塞博特恩大战时期 这种病毒夺去了无数生命
Cybonic plague was engineered in the Decepticons' Biological Warfare Program...
灰死病是霸天虎生物战争计划的产物
by Megatron himself.
由威震天亲自研发
You have a cure, don't you?
你…有解药 是吧？
No cure...
无药可救…
Optimus, please, save your strength.
擎天柱 拜托 保存一点体力吧
Would Megatron create a disease without having a cure?
威震天能制造病毒 怎么会不造解药？
I mean what if he caught it by accident?
我是说 万一他不小心感染了怎么办？
It's not like we can ask Megatron, Jack.
可我们没法拷问威震天了 杰克
He's pushing up lugnuts.
他已经上西天了
But we might be able to access the Decepticon database.
但是 没准可以查询霸天虎的数据库
For the moment, we still have a fix on their warship's location.
目前 我们还掌握着他们战舰的位置
Bumblebee, come with.
大黄蜂 跟我走
Arcee, quickly.
阿尔茜 尽快吧
Let's start with the lab.
我们从实验室开始找
I'm in the network.
我进入他们的网络了
Rachet...
救护车…
Were you...
你有没有…
Infected? No.
被感染？没有
If it's here, I don't see it.
数据真在这里吗 我没找到
Are you certain, Arcee?
你能确定吗 阿尔茜？
I searched every file, nothing.
我搜索了所有文件 没找到
Well, search again! Clearly you missed something!
那就再找一遍！你肯定有遗漏！
I scanned the entire database.
整个数据库我都扫描遍了！
Did you use a redundant quantum algorithm?
你用过冗余量子算法吗？
Don't tell me how to research.
别用那些名词吓唬我
You think you are the only one who cares about Optimus?
你以为只有你自己关心擎天柱吗？
What is it?
怎么回事？
What is it? What's going on?
怎么了？出什么事了？
It's Megatron.
是威震天
He's alive.
他还…活着
What?
什么？
That's not possible!
那不可能！
But I'm staring right at him.
可我看见的确实是他
Good news is,
好消息是
Megatron isn't exactly staring back.
威震天没有回应我的目光
Megatron?
威震天？
He's critical, hooked up to life support.
他不行了 全靠生命维持系统撑着
Time to finish this once and for all.
该把他一劳永逸地解决掉了
Wait! Don't!
慢着！别动手！
One good reason, fast!
给我个好理由 快说！
Megatron may be Optimus's only hope for survival.
威震天或许是救活擎天柱的唯一希望
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Does he display brainwave activity?
他的脑电波还有活动吗？
Spiking hard, his sick mind still at work.
很强烈 他的病态思维仍在运转
Perfect. If a cure exists, Megatron maybe the only one who knows it.
太好了！如果真的有解药 威震天可能是唯一知道底细的人
You must enter his brain and find it.
你们必须进入他的大脑 找到解药！
Enter Megatron's brain?
进入威震天的大脑？
Rachet, are you out of your fragging mind?
救护车 你是不是疯了？
The Decepticon laboratory should contain all the equipment you need for a cortical psychic patch.
霸天虎实验室应该有所需的全部设备 你可以执行大脑皮层通灵驳接
No way. Have you ever even performed the procedure?
不行 你以前有没有执行过这套程序？
No. But I have thoroughly studied the theoretical literature...
没有 但我仔细研究过理论资料…
invented by Decepticons, outlawed by Autobots.
它是霸天虎发明的 但被汽车人明令禁止
Whoa, can't we just haul Megatron through the GroundBridge, buy us some time to figure this out?
哇 我们用环陆桥把威震天运走 时间不是会充裕一点吗？
Time is one thing that Optimus does not have!
擎天柱可没有那么充裕的时间！
One of you must try this！
你们俩必须有人试一下！
I will not allow Optimus to pass knowing that Megatron will outlive him!
我绝不容许在威震天归西之前 就要给擎天柱送终！
Ratchet, I would lay down my life for Optimus, anytime, anywhere.
救护车 我愿意为擎天柱拼命 无论何时何地
But a mind-body split...
可要说灵魂出窍…
You will?
你要去吗？
Are you... sure, Bumblebee?
你有…把握吗 大黄蜂？
Bee's the best scout there is.
小蜂是我们最棒的侦察兵
Why has the elctromagnetic shielding not been repaired?
电磁防护罩为什么还没修好？
The crews are working as quickly as they can, Lord...
舰员正在尽全力抢修 陛下…
We are leaking a trail!
我们的航迹暴露了！
All the Autobots need do to pinpoint our position is to access the correct frequency wavelength.
汽车人只要访问正确的频段波长 就能获得我们的准确位置
Accelerate your efforts!
动作再快点！
Yes, Lord Starscream.
遵命 红蜘蛛陛下
Doctor in the house.
医官报到
Ah, Knock Out, and how is the patient doing today?
啊 击倒 病人今天状况如何？
Same old...
老样子…
An inglorious fate that he should remain in this vegetative state...
保持这种植物人状态 真是让他无地自容
On the contrary, Megatron's body may be scrap metal,
正相反 威震天的身体也许成了废铁
but his mind is still percolating.
但他的思维还是很活跃的
Keep that to yourself!
你自己知道就行了！
That blasted Soundwave sees and hears everything.
那该死的声波好像有千里眼和顺风耳
The eyes and ears of the Decepticons.
他是霸天虎的耳目嘛
Well, as long as their master remains in limbo, so does their cause.
只要他们的主子一天不醒 他们就是群无头苍蝇
The Decepticons deserve a strong, alert leader.
霸天虎急需一位强悍的 警醒的领袖
One who would require a loyal second-in-command.
这位领袖也需要一个忠诚的副官
Hmhmhm, a candidate would need to earn that post by making a strong case to said eyes and ears.
要想坐上副官的位置 必须干得漂亮点 才能让那个“耳目”闭嘴
A case for showing mercy, Lord Starscream?
需要发发慈悲吗 红蜘蛛陛下？
You scratch my back, I scratch yours.
你敬我一尺 我敬你一丈
Ratchet, we are ready.
救护车 我们准备好了
Initiate cortical psychic patch.
启动大脑皮层通灵驳接
Communications downlink activated.
通讯下行链路激活
This will allow us to see and hear everything Bumblebee does
这样我们就能利用大黄蜂的视觉和听觉
while within Megatron's subconscious mind.
进入威震天的潜意识
Whoa, where is that?
哇 那是什么地方？
Bee says it looks like Kaon, the Decepticon Capital back on Cybertron.
小蜂说那儿像是卡隆 霸天虎在塞博特恩上的首都
Ratch, Optimus's vitals.
老救 大哥的情况很差
I know.
我知道
Quickly, Bumblebee.
快点 大黄蜂
I know you are in unknown territory,
我知道那是个陌生环境
but you must figure out where information might be filed in Megatron's mind.
但你必须在威震天的意识里 找到信息的大致储存位置
Bumblebee, that is not Optimus,
大黄蜂 那不是擎天柱
but a figment of Megatron's mind.
只是威震天的思维幻像
It cannot see or hear you.
他看不见 也听不到你
Mmmmhahaha, Optimus Prime!
哈哈 擎天柱！
Your Autobot armies are defeated.
你的汽车人部队战败了
Bow before your new master.
向你的新主人鞠躬吧
Never, Megatron.
我决不低头 威震天
One shall stand, one shall fall.
不是你死 就是我亡
So be it.
那就来吧
That never happened.
这事我可没见过
It's not a memory.
这不是记忆
We're seeing Kaon as Megatron has recreated it in his darkest dreams.
我们看见的卡隆 是威震天在他的黑暗梦境里重建的
Megatron, your treachery ends here.
威震天 你的恶行到此为止吧
The Autobot scout.
汽车人侦察兵
The punishment for trespassing in my domain is your destruction!
胆敢擅闯我的领地 我让你灰飞烟灭！
How can this be?
这怎么可能？
Megatron can't touch Bee?
威震天碰不到小蜂吗？
Because he's not a creation of Megatron's mind,
因为他不是威震天的意识产物
Bumblebee is immune to his physical attack.
大黄蜂对他的物理攻击免疫
You are not wearing phase displacement armor.
你没有穿戴相移盔甲
Your eyes track my movements, so you are not a hologram.
你的眼睛可以追踪我的动作 说明你不是全息图像
And I do not believe in spirits.
我也不相信灵魂论
So tell me, scout, what are you?
快告诉我 侦察兵 你是什么东西？
Megatron!
威震天！
Uho, special guest stars.
啊哦 特邀嘉宾来了
This is not good.
这可不太妙
You are real. They were not!
你是真实的 他们不是！
Hehehe, a cortical psychic patch.
大脑皮层通灵驳接
How unexpected.
真想不到啊
We've stirred Megatron from his oblivion.
我们扰乱了威震天的无意识状态
He's becoming self-aware.
他开始恢复自我意识了！
If this is my subconscious,
如果这是我的潜意识
what are you doing inside my head?
你在我的脑子里干什么？
Come on, Bee. What are you doing in there?
加油 小蜂 你到底在干嘛？
Knock Out, if you would be so kind as to provide your expert medical opinion to Soundwave,
击倒 麻烦你向声波讲一下 专家的治疗意见
for the historical record.
以便记录在案
Simply put, unaided, Megatron could remain in this deadless slumber forever.
简单来说 如果没有外力协助 威震天会永远保持这种假死状态
Our master would not have wanted to be seen this way.
我们的主人不会希望自己成为这个样子
To stand idly by while he remains captive in his own body, is not just.
眼看着他的灵魂被禁锢 我们却无所事事 这不公平
Brainwave activity, not evidence of consciousness, but merely of an endless dream
脑电波的活动不能证明他拥有意识 只是陷入了无穷的梦境
from which Megatron may never wake.
威震天或许永远都无法醒过来
Soundwave, we must face reality.
声波 我们必须面对现实
Megatron is lost to us.
我们已经痛失威震天
The only honorable option, would be to show him mercy.
唯一体面的选择 就是让他解脱
A simple throw off the switch.
只是拨动一个开关而已
Quick, painless, compassionate.
迅速 没有痛苦 充满怜悯
Ratchet, are you hearing this?
救护车 你听到了吗？
If Megatron perishes,
如果威震天死了
Bumblebee's mind will remain separated from his body, forever.
大黄蜂的意识就会和他的身体分离 永远分离
We'll lose Bumblebee and Optimus?
那我们岂不要同时失去大黄蜂和擎天柱？
The only way you could have entered my mind, is via cortical psychic patch.
你能进入我的意识的唯一办法 就是通过大脑皮层通灵驳接
But the question remains...
但是还有问题
What happened to me?
我到底是怎么了？
The SpaceBridge explosion.
太空桥爆炸
And yet if, if you're in my head, I am not one with the Allspark.
另外 如果你能进入我的大脑 就说明我还没彻底死亡
So tell me, scout, do I still function?
告诉我 侦察兵 我是不是还活着？
Bumblebee, we are out of time!
大黄蜂 我们没时间了！
Cybonic plague?
灰死病？
Somebody beside myself is, is unwell?
除了我自己 还有人被…感染了？
Optimus!
擎天柱！
Such irony!
真是讽刺！
That after ages of endless battle,
经历了连年的战争
the mighty Optimus Prime is fell by a simple virus from the distant past!
伟大的擎天柱居然在远古时代的 简单病毒面前败下阵来！
And what makes you think I would save the life of my oldest enemy?
你凭什么以为 我会出手拯救我的老对头？
Megatron, your treachery is...
威震天 你的恶行…
Oh, and just what is it that I want most, scout?
噢 那么我最想要的是什么呢 侦察兵？
Haha, did you not see, I do slay Optimus by my own hand,
你没看到吗 擎天柱可以被我亲手杀死
at will, whenever I desire!
我随心所欲 想杀就杀！
Bee told Megatron if he lets the plague virus destroy the real Optimus,
小蜂告诉威震天 如果他让病毒毁掉擎天柱的话
Megatron will never get the chance to do it himself.
他就再也没机会亲自动手了
Smart!
聪明！
Twisted!
变态！
Soundwave, do I take your silence to mean you concur with Knock Out's medical expertise?
声波 我可不可以认为 你用沉默来表示认同击倒的专业见解？
Speak now, or forever hold your peace.
要么开口 要么永远闭上你的臭嘴
Going.
说啊…
Scrap!
糟了！
After our deep history together, to not watch the spark end from Optimus's eyes with my very own...
这么多恩恩怨怨都走过来了 如果不能亲眼看到擎天柱熄灭火种的话…
Well-played, scout.
干得好 侦察兵
The chemical formula for the cure you seek.
这就是你要找的解药配方
Not that I expect you to know how to read it.
我并不指望你能读懂
Not yet.
现在不行
And how am I to accomplish terminating Optimus as you proposed,
既然你提议 让我亲手终结擎天柱的生命
while I'm traped here in a perpetual day-dream?
可我怎么能摆脱这个无限循环的白日梦呢？
Once you release me from this prison, you will have the cure.
只要你帮我逃出这个监狱 就可以得到解药
Come on, come on.
快点 快点！
You must guarantee my recovery, or Optimus fades to gunmetal grey.
你必须保证让我复原 否则 擎天柱只能变灰 然后死掉
The REAL Optimus.
我说的是真正的擎天柱
Arcee, we have the formula.
阿尔茜 配方已经到手
Disconnect Bumblebee, now!
断开大黄蜂的驳接 快！
You were watching, you tricked me!
你们在监视 你骗了我！
No, take me with you! Take me! Take me! Take me!
不！带我一起走！带我走…
Hurry, Bee.
快点啊 小蜂！
What in...
怎么…
Intruders!
入侵者！
Allow me!
让我来吧！
Huh, it was the inevitable outcome.
唉 结局在所难免
Uhhh... of course it would be wrong to allow Megatron to perish by an Autobot's hand,
当然了 不该让威震天牺牲在汽车人的手里
Knock Out.
击倒
That's it. Steady.
就这样 稳住
Please, reserve the hero's welcome for my physician, and my scout.
请各位把对英雄的欢呼留给我的医师 还有我的侦察兵
- Alright. - Yes!
- 没事了 - 是啊！
And how is the patient doing today?
病人今天的情况如何？
Funny, you should ask.
这话问得好
Not sure what the Bots did in there.
不清楚汽车人在他脑子里动了什么手脚
But Megatron's registering zero brainwave activity.
但是威震天的脑电波已经归零了
Mmm, meaning?
嗯 说明什么？
Physically he is stable, but now,
表面来看他很稳定 但现在
there is no one home.
他的…灵魂消失了
I'm out.
我出来了
Or should I say, IN!
或许该说…进来了！